# **Phoebe Badcock**

Buckinghamshire <a href="mailto:phoebe.badcock@mail.com">phoebe.badcock@mail.com</a> github.com/PhoebeBC phoebebc.github.io/Portfolio-Webpage/

Software developer, designing and building products to gain relevant experience, actively seeking opportunities to join the exciting tech sector and become a valuable team member. Over 3 years of experience at a finance start up.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

- SQL (Postgres Database)
- Flask & APIs
- Selenium & Webdriver
- GitHub & GitHub Pages
- Jira & Confluence
- Pycharm & VSCode

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Independent

January 2024–Present

- Personal Portfolio (Web Development): Producing a website informing users of projects and experience.
   Advanced my HTML & CSS skills and boosted ability to research solutions online pushing webpage creation time down by 50%.
- Storm Website (Full Stack Development): Creating a functioning mobile website for a hockey club in-line
  with client requirements. Improves communication between organizers and partakers, allowing for more
  people to play and pay pushing up funding by 25%. Utilising MERN (Mongo DB Express React and
  Node.JS) and collaborating with front end developer to build site.
- Computer Science Fundamentals: Planned six days of intense learning with senior software engineer.
   Covered Unit Testing, VM Ubuntu for Linux, Networking, Computer Architecture, Networks TCP, TLS protocol, CIA Triad confidentiality Integrity availability, Docker, AWS servers and C programming.

# STRATEGIC ANALYST (Promoted to Senior January 2023)

September 2020-January 2024

Snap Finance UK

- Building MI Dashboard: Constructed base for new company wide data dashboard. Improved data refresh
  time form every hour to instantly upon page refresh. Used Flask, APIs and Python backend embedding
  SQL queries accessing data from the Postgres Database. With Jinja and Bootstrap supporting the
  frontend for interactive, customizable diagrams, graphs, metrics.
- **Test Driven Development**: Optimized testing of decision changes. Time taken to test each change was reduced from 6 hours to 1 by implementing **Selenium** and **Webdriver** to push test applications through in QA environments. Results were shared via Jira to the machine learning engineers.
- Company-wide **Automation**: Over 10 process across five departments were upgraded including the customer lending complaints process, which went from 2 hours to under 30 seconds for each review. Collaborated with junior colleague to extend automation efforts externally using **APIs** and SFTPs.
- Customer Outcomes Review: Successfully completed FCA requested review of the five year history of the
  company. By constructing insightful data tables within the Postgres Database, £5 million saved in costs,
  and the FCA was fully satisfied with our customer outcomes.
- CRA Handling: Effectively oversaw credit reporting, including regular testing and checks of the files, to credit bureaus, fostering strong relationships through clear communication.

## **EDUCATION**

**TRENT COLLEGE** 

**UNIVERSITY OF WARWICK** 

October2017- July 2020

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics: First Class with Honors

A Levels: A\*A\*AA Further Maths, Maths, Physics, Chemistry

GCSEs: 11 - A\*(6), A(5)

September 2010–July 2017